<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul Larkin</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paul Larkin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Paul Larkin</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 15:32:05 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Unsplash API in Kotlin</title>
      <link>/work/kotlinapi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 22:22:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/kotlinapi/</guid>
      <description>During the Covid-19 lockdown, I took the time to get familiar with both mobile development and the Kotlin programming language. I will start by saying it not the prettiest code as am still currently learning. The project was a small milestone in my understanding of both APIs and the Kotlin language. I wanted to challenge myself with an API I wasn&amp;rsquo;t familiar with so that I would have to read the developers documents and put in the time to make it work error by error.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Premium SMS Malware Analysis</title>
      <link>/work/androidmalwareone/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 08:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/androidmalwareone/</guid>
      <description>Sample hash: cf661506978f088f276a5a5bc4f0ea71101f99941840dd0864b2068ee2eb2271
In this project, I will be detailing the steps that I took when analyzing a malicious sample after completing Maddie Stones Android Reverse Engineering 101 course. I found the course an excellent practical introduction and overview of reverse engineering mobile malware.
The course is available at https://maddiestone.github.io/AndroidAppRE/ if your interested I can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it an enough.
As for the APK itself, the sample was found around September time back in 2019 and was added to sk3ptre malware samples Github repository in February 2020.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 20:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name Paul and I’m a UK-based university student. In my spare time, I enjoy bring my ideas to life through programming, design and participating in tech events.
I&amp;rsquo;m currently learning about mobile development, UX and re-learning frontend development technologies so you can expect more posts in these realms soon!
Thanks for dropping by!
You can reach me at paularkin (@) hotmail.com or follow me on twitter
  Credits Powered by hugo | modified theme based on hello-friend-ng by rhazdon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Static Analysis For Windows Malware</title>
      <link>/work/staticanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 20:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/staticanalysis/</guid>
      <description>In the following blog post, I am going walk through several of the steps I took to start learning about static analysis for windows malware using both samclass.info and the Practical Malware Analysis book. The examples below are from the books exercise materials. The tools vary to the book recommendations as I found others that speed up the process.
Lab01-02.exe – Packed exe. To start, I ran the sample through detect-it-easy which indicated that the sample was packed with UPX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Learnt From Competing in PicoCTF 2018</title>
      <link>/posts/picoctf2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2018 20:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/picoctf2018/</guid>
      <description>In this blog post, I want to share my thoughts on competing in a live CTF for the first time. The event was Pico CTF hosted online and created by Carnegie Mellon University (CMU) Cybersecurity and the world number two CTF team currently at the time of writing Plaid Parliament of Pwning (PPP).
It is an engaging event with a series of different challenges. That on progression push you out your comfort zone just enough for you to have to research and learn new tools and techniques to capture the flag and earn points.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyber Gamification: Immersive Labs and TryHackMe</title>
      <link>/posts/gamificiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 15:32:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gamificiation/</guid>
      <description>All of us have heard of how gaming can become addictive. As previous gamer I know all too well how addictive and competitive video games can become. But, what if we can apply that same magic to more positive skill training? Specifically in cyber security given that hands on nature of various techniques and roles in the sector.
I&amp;rsquo;m going to do just that, well from my own personal perspective and experience with cyber wargaming platforms such as immersive labs and TryHackMe.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Exe to Pixels: Image Generation For Malware Classification</title>
      <link>/work/fromexetopixel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2020 22:22:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/fromexetopixel/</guid>
      <description>This write-up came about after learning about image classification from fast.ai&amp;rsquo;s online course. The course started out by teaching participants to classify cats and dogs images, this was cool at the time but then my mind shifted to can this be used to classify malware and how? The simple answer, yes, but finding a dataset with benign images now that was a problem. So in this write-up, I will showing the steps I took while i started to build a dataset with benign greyscale images using windows executables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leading a Team for MagicCTF</title>
      <link>/posts/magicctf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 08:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/magicctf/</guid>
      <description>Today, I am writing up a quick blog post on my thoughts and experience leading a team and competing in Mid-Atlantic Gigabit Innovation Collaboratory (MAGIC) CTF.
We participated locally on registered sites while the competition end was held online in the cloud accessed by SSH. All the challenges were unlocked at once and sitting on the server within level folders progressing in difficulty. Which was odd as it was the first time i had seen this format before.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Twitter as an Educational Tool</title>
      <link>/posts/twittered/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 22:14:59 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/twittered/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to share how you can take social media and leverage it as an educational tool. This is most prevalent in relation to Twitter, you can turn your news feed into a gold mine of information, simply by following the right people in your subject area of interest.
For me, that would be the computer security community and the steps I took doing this myself. To start off, I personally created a new twitter account specifically for this purpose and started following several open source content creators, malware analysts, and security researchers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Graduate Re-Brand &amp; Logo Design</title>
      <link>/work/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 15:34:47 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/graduate/</guid>
      <description>I developed this project after entering my creative brief and mock up for redesign of southern regional college, graduate restaurant. The organisers where looking for concept ideas based on the remodelling and renovation of the restaurants interior.
My design style at the time was heavy focused on modern minimalism design trends with muted or neutral colours and designs that I had seen other trendy restaurants from around the world implement in their own ways.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>